Owen Campbell

Email Website Location

Mobile Phone +44 (0)7799 111652 owen.campbell@empiria.co.uk owencampbell.me.uk

Helsby, Cheshire UK

Profile

I am a Chartered Engineer and have worked in the information management field, both in the UK and overseas, since the early 1990s.

I first implemented Agresso in 1998 and, since 2001, have specialised in this field via my consulting company, Empiria Ltd.

I have a thorough understanding of technology and business processes and practical experience of many diverse operational environments.

I have the soft skills to operate effectively in the board room, the IT and Finance departments and with end users, system administrators and system suppliers.

I have a proven track record of delivering practical, successful solutions and previous clients willing to support that claim.

I am completely independent of any organisation, other than my own company, and receive no commission or fees from any software supplier or recruitment agency.

I have a small network of trusted, highly skilled and experienced colleagues whom I can call upon to supplement my own efforts as and when necessary.

Major Projects

Some of the more notable projects undertaken in recent years include:

- Fixed Assets Implementation for a UK Housing Group Design and implementation of component accounting for a UK Housing Group with a portfolio of over 25 000 properties
- New Agresso Implementation for a Multi-National UK PLC Design and implementation of a new Agresso system for a UK PLC with over 100 multi-national subsidiaries and including full data migration of all historical transactions
- New Agresso Implementation for a National UK Retail Company Design and implementation of external interfaces, reporting templates, and historical data-load for a new Agresso implementation. Successful go-live within 6 month deadline.
- Agresso Roll Out to an Overseas Subsidiary of a UK Engineering Company Data-loading, interface design, configuration and testing for a fast-track, high-profile implementation of a new Canadian acquisition within a live UK system. (150 new users within a 1200 user system).
- System Integration for a UK Engineering Company Successful integration of Agresso and a document management system to provide tendering and specification functionality (1000 user system)
- Roll Out of a Standardised Configuration to all Subsidiaries of a UK Financial PLC Design and implementation of a standardised configuration across a multi-country, multi-company operation (approx. 100 subsidiary companies)
- Implementation of Project Based Accounting for a UK Software PLC Design and implementation of the addition of project accounting to an existing multi-country operational system
- Bespoke Interface Design for a UK Higher Education Establishment Design and implementation of an interface between Agresso and a student record system

Owen Campbell

Mobile Phone Email Website Location

+44 (0)7799 111652 owen.campbell@empiria.co.uk

owencampbell.me.uk Helsby, Cheshire UK

Knowledge, Experience and Skills

Technology Agresso, ARC, ActiveReports, Excelerator, ARW, ACT

Oracle, MS SQL Server, Postgresql, MySQL

Ruby, Rails, Python, Django

Powershell, Bash

Sectors Professional Services, Retail, Finance, Higher Education, NHS Trusts, National and

Local Government, Charities

Project Types System Review, Selection, Implementation, Configuration, Testing, Troubleshooting,

Upgrading, Interfacing, Supporting, Reporting

Employment History

2001 – Current Owner and Director, Empiria Ltd

In March 2001, along with two colleagues, I left Eutech to form my own Agresso

consulting company, Empiria Ltd.

1998 – 2001 Agresso System Manager, Eutech Ltd

In 1998, ICI decided to sell Eutech and I became the lead engineer on a project to implement Agresso. I then became the manager of that system and led its mainte-

nance, development and support.

1994 – 1998 **Technology Project Manager**, Eutech Ltd

Eutech was a wholly owned subsidiary of ICI PLC which provided engineering con-

sultancy services to the process industries.

I joined at its inception in a role providing technical leadership of collaborative R&D projects between ICI PLC and other EU organisations. I particularly specialised in

the innovative design and use of relational databases.

1990 – 1994 **Project Engineer**, ICI PLC

I joined ICI as a graduate engineer and worked on a variety of engineering projects

for ICI businesses in the UK.

Education and Qualifications

1995 **CEng MIET** Chartered Engineer, Member of the Institution of Engineering Technology (www.theiet.org Formerly the Institution of Electrical Engineering)

1990 **BEng (Hons)** Engineering Science and Technology (University of Loughborough)

Interests and Hobbies

I am a voluntary senior manager for the UK Scout Association (District Commissioner for the Mersey Weaver Scout District: www.merseyweaverscouts.org.uk).

The role involves overall responsibility for the delivery of Scouting to the District's 1250 young people and line management of its 250 adult volunteers.